<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jeremy Yeaton</title>
    <link>https://jeremyyeaton.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jeremyyeaton.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyyeaton.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jeremyyeaton.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ambiguity in negative dependencies</title>
      <link>https://jeremyyeaton.github.io/project/negation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyyeaton.github.io/project/negation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many languages exhibit Negative Concord, that is when two negative items are interpreted as a single negation. For example, if a man has robbed a bank and says &lt;em&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t do nothing&lt;/em&gt;, we understand this as &lt;em&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything&lt;/em&gt; even though he used two negative words&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt;. By contrast, if a mother comes home from work and finds her child sitting in front of the television, she might accuse them of having done nothing all day, to which they might reply &lt;em&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t do nothing&lt;/em&gt;. The child, however means exactly the opposite of what the bank robber meant &amp;ndash; that they &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. French speakers have been shown to easily access both of these readings (Déprez et al. 2015), so we&amp;rsquo;ve undertaken a series of experiments to see how context (Déprez &amp;amp; Yeaton 2018), and prosody (Yeaton et al. forthcoming) might be employed to convey meaning. We also want to examine how good listeners are at leveraging these prosodic signals to access the meaning that the speaker intended (Loder et al. forthcoming).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical learning in noise</title>
      <link>https://jeremyyeaton.github.io/project/sequence-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyyeaton.github.io/project/sequence-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a series of experiments using a motor sequence learning task, we are examining the effect of different types of noise on the baboons&#39; ability to extract a regularity (e.g.: AB) from a sequence. For example, if the baboon saw the pair AB 100 times, but each time it was in a different position in the sequence (e.g.: XABX, XXAB, ABXX, etc.), will that impede their ability to learn the relationship between A and B relative to if they only saw ABCD every trial?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a parallel project, we are constructing a computational model of this learning process to better understand how the process takes place in baboons, and how that differs from in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
